Kreigh Collins Cartoons
Kreigh Collins Cartoons
1966-1968
Collins, Kreigh, 1908-
7 linear ft.
Original cartoons from the comic strips Kevin the Bold and Up Anchor.
2652418
Biographical History
Kreigh Collins (1908-1974) was an American cartoonist, illustrator and painter. He was the creator of the comic strip Kevin the Bold.
Born in Davenport, Iowa, Collins received his formal training as an artist at the Cincinnati Art Academy and the Cleveland Art School. He worked for many years as a magazine illustrator before signing on with the NEA syndicate to produce his first newspaper comic strip, Mitzi McCoy. In late 1950, this Sunday-page contemporary melodrama about a wealthy heiress made an abrupt transformation into a late-Medieval adventure strip. Kevin the Bold first appeared October 1, 1950. This beautifully drawn Sunday strip, focused on one of Mitzi McCoy's 15th Century Irish ancestors, ran in syndication for nearly twenty years. In 1968, Collins began work on the strip Up Anchor, a modern tale about sailing, loosely based on the real-life experiences of the Collins family. Up Anchor ran until 1972.
In addition to his magazine and newspaper work, Kreigh Collins illustrated a number of books during his career, including The Perilous Island: A Story of Mystery in the Aleutians (Philadelphia: Winston, 1942), The Amazing Story of Christopher Columbus (Washington, DC: Review and Herald Pub. Association, 1961) and David Livingston (Washington, DC: Review and Herald Pub. Association, 1961). Collins was an active painter throughout his life and completed a number of public murals in and around Grand Rapids, Michigan. Kreigh Collins died in 1974 at the age of 66.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Kreigh Collins Cartoons collection contains original Sunday cartoons from the comic strips Kevin the Bold and Up Anchor. Sunday cartoon: traces of graphite, blue pencil, opaque white, zipatone, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, most approx. 20 x 30 in.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Collins, Kreigh, 1908-; Newspaper Enterprise Association.; Kevin the bold (comic strip); Up anchor (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; Adventure stories -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Sailing -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Newspaper Enterprise Association, Inc., 1967-1969.
Inventory
- Kevin the Bold cartoons
  Click here for detailed inventory.
  - Sunday cartoons, Jan 1966 - Mar 1966; 12 items (Box 1)
  - Sunday cartoons, Apr 1966 - Aug 1966; 15 items (Box 2)
  - Sunday cartoons, Sep 1966 - Dec 1966; 14 items (Box 3)
  - Sunday cartoons, Jan 1967 - Apr 1967; 14 items (Box 4)
  - Sunday cartoons, May 1967 - Sep 1967; 15 items (Box 5)
  - Sunday cartoons, Oct 1967 - Dec 1967; 14 items (Box 6)
  - Sunday cartoons, Jan 1968 - Jun 1968 (Box 7)
  - Sunday cartoons, Jul 1968 - Dec 1968 (Box 8)
- Up Anchor cartoons
  - Sunday cartoons, Nov 1968 - Dec 1968 (Box 8)